UX Design

Business Information Systems

De Montfort University

RICHARD MARSHALL

CONTACT

PROFILE



07429362001



rich-marshall@Hotmail.co.uk



linkedin.com/in/richamarshall



richmarshall.co.uk

I am a First Class 2019 Graduate with a unique skill set including excellent interpersonal skills in combination with a strong technical background. I have developed a passion for user experience and have tailored many aspects of my degree, including my Final Year Project, to reflect this.

I was Ski and Snowboard captain of my university Snowsports team for two years. I took a leadership role during this time and consistently raised the standard of the team and the results gained.

EDUCATION

EMPLOYMENT

Business Information Systems SEPTEMBER 2016 - JULY 2019 Degree Classification: First Class

DMU SNOW Society - Snowboard Captain SEPTEMBER 2018 - JULY 2019

De Montfort University

Dauntsey's School

SEPTEMBER 2007 - JULY 2014

A Levels: Maths - Economics - Physics

GCSEs: 9 As

Captain: Rugby Team

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JULY 2013

Went unbeaten for 2 years including the year

under my captaincy.

Interaction Design Foundation

JUNE 2020 - CURRENT

Currently enrolled and working through the UX design material on the IDF

Immediate Media Co.

CMS and Error-Clean-Up Assistant

SEPTEMBER 2019 - CURRENT

I worked on a website migration project with Immediate Media Co. transferring data onto the new "Fabric" system. Most recently, I fixed broken content and page errors to increase overall site health.

The brands I have worked on include BBC Countryfile, BBC Discover Wildlife, Homestyle UK, Your Home, EKBB, KBB Daily, Who Do You Think You Are and BBC Classical Music

The Winterbourne

Barista and Bartender

SEPTEMBER 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

Customer facing role in a French influenced country pub. I was afforded a lot of autonomy and was able to manage myself during this period of work. This taught me to be confident in making my own decisions.

I trained other staff members and created new menu items when new drinks and desert cocktails were needed.

SKILLS

EMPLOYMENT

User Experience
Adobe XD
Html
CSS
Responsive Design
Git
Google Analytics
Power BI

User Experience and Adobe XD:

I spent a significant portion of my degree working on my Final Year Project where I designed using XD and focused my research on UX and how user psychology affected their behaviour while using systems.

HTML, CSS, Responsive Design and GIT:

I have extensively used HTML, CSS and to a lesser extent, JavaScript while completing assignments in my degree and doing some freelance website development. Throughout all of this I have maintained mobile first design and have managed version control with GIT.

Google Analytics and Power BI:

While on my 6-week internship for Immediate Media Co. I used both platforms to assist the UX and Business Analytics teams and provide them with data they required. I Also created analytics dashboards with Power BI from the data collected.

ITIL:

I completed the ITIL foundation in my second year of Uni and passed the certification.

REFERENCES

Available on request

Immediate Media Co.

Intern

JULY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Intern for Immediate Media Co. in London and Bristol. I spent time with several teams, including: UX, Marketing, Business Analysis, Apps and Data. This gave great insights into how a mid-sized publishing firm operates across all areas.

I worked with Google analytics, Power BI, Swift and Node JS and Node RED. I was allowed to manage my own time on individual projects and a lot of research in these areas of potential future projects.

Yodel Ski School. Niigata – Japan

Ski and Snowboard Instructor

DECEMBER 2015 - MAY 2016

Taught a range of mostly Japanese, Australian and Chinese clients in private and group sessions. This developed my interpersonal and presentation skills and improved my understanding of other cultures. I gained the ability to manage my time and lead/run a session on my own and was able to consistently maintain a safe working environment.

Giraffe

Barista and Bartender

APRIL 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

Customer facing role in a 200-cover restaurant. I worked and thrived under pressure and this taught me to be confident in making my own decisions and prioritising work. Working in a high-pressure environment like this ensured that I was able to fix problems and sort out situations as they occurred without having to resort to support from higher level staff.